<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual Green Tech</title>
    <link>https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Visual Green Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021, Nitya Narasimhan; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 12:14:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#VisualGreenTech: Challenge Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/post/challenge-retro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/post/challenge-retro/</guid>
      <description>Photo Credit: Unsplash
 About #VisualGreenTech On April 1 (2021), we launched the #VisualGreenTech challenge with an announcement on the HelloWorld show and a blog post on the Microsoft Green Tech Community blog.
The challenge itself consisted of 24 prompts shared on social media with the intent of raising awareness and action around topics related to sustainable living and green technology in community and workplace contexts. Readers were invited to review a linked resource, think about a question posed in the daily prompt, and respond with a visual that reflected a related insight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World! It&#39;s #EarthDay!</title>
      <link>https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/post/helloearth-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/post/helloearth-day/</guid>
      <description>April 22, 2021 was officially designated EarthDay, a day (or days) where folks around the world organize events and conversations to drive actionable impact on climate change.
Within the Microsoft Developer Relations team, we decided to run a challenge of our own - the #VisualGreenTech challenge, with 24 daily prompts that were designed to raise awareness and action from the community around both sustainable living (community) and sustainable software engineering (technology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About #VisualGreenTech</title>
      <link>https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sketchthedocs.dev/visual-green-tech/about/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The website will broadly explore visual storytelling as a tool for increasing awareness and action around sustainability practices and sustainable software engineering (greentech) in our communities and workplaces.
Visual Storytelling refers to the use of visual elements (fonts, graphics, composition, color) to create content (sketchnotes, visual metaphors, characters) that help make a complex message easier to understand, retain, and recall. This can include:
 Visual Guides | sketchnotes that provide &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo; overviews of content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
